discourse.org 2014-06-19

# Discourse Privacy Policy

### 1\. ACKNOWLEDGEMENT AND ACCEPTANCE OF TERMS

Civilized Discourse Construction Kit, Inc. (“CDCK”) owns and operates Discourse.org, an open source discussion platform, (“Platform”). Clients license our Platform and in some cases, we may host the discussion forum for their website visitors. 

This Privacy Statement describes the data we collect and how it is used for visitors of the Discourse.org website (It is not [the privacy policy for our hosted forums](http://www.discourse.org/hosted-forum-privacy-policy)). 

CDCK is committed to protecting your privacy. This Privacy Statement sets forth our current privacy practices with regard to the information we collect when you or your computer interact with our website. By accessing discourse.org, you acknowledge and fully understand discourse.org's Privacy Statement and freely consent to the information collection and use practices described in this Website Privacy Statement. 

### 2\. PARTICIPATING MERCHANT POLICIES

Related services and offerings with links from this website, including vendor sites, have their own privacy statements that can be viewed by clicking on the corresponding links within each respective website. Online merchants and others who participate in discourse.org services are encouraged to participate in industry privacy initiatives and to take a responsible attitude towards consumer privacy. However, since we do not have direct control over the policies or practices of participating merchants and other third parties, we are not responsible for the privacy practices or contents of those sites. We recommend and encourage that you always review the privacy policies of merchants and other third parties before you provide any personal information or complete any transaction with such parties. 

### 3\. INFORMATION WE COLLECT AND HOW WE USE IT

discourse.org collects certain information from and about its users three ways: 

**a. Web Server Logs**

When you visit our Website, we may track information to administer the site and analyze its usage. Examples of information we may track include: 

  * Your Internet protocol address.
  * The kind of browser or computer you use.
  * Number of links you click within the site.
  * State or country from which you accessed the site.
  * Date and time of your visit.
  * Name of your Internet service provider
  * Web page you linked to our site from.
  * Pages you viewed on the site.

**b. Browser Cookies**

discourse.org may use cookies to personalize or enhance your user experience. A cookie is a small text file that is placed on your hard disk by a Web page server. Cookies cannot be used to run programs or deliver viruses to your computer. Cookies are uniquely assigned to you, and can only be read by a Web Server in the domain that issued the cookie to you. 

One of the primary purposes of cookies is to provide a convenience feature to save you time. For example, if you personalize a web page, or navigate within a site, a cookie helps the site to recall your specific information on subsequent visits. Hence, this simplifies the process of delivering relevant content and eases site navigation by providing and saving your preferences and login information as well as providing personalized functionality.  

You have the ability to accept or decline cookies. Most Web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies. If you reject cookies by changing your browser settings then be aware that this may disable some of the functionality on our Website.  

**c. Personal Information from Users**

CDCK does not release any type of personally identifiable information out to anyone, except if required by law. Visitors to our website can register to purchase services or use free member services. For these types of registrations, we will ask for the relevant information. You may also be asked to disclose personal information to us so that we can provide assistance and information to you. For example, such data may be warranted in order to provide online technical support and troubleshooting. 

We will not disclose information we collect from you to third parties without your permission except to the extent necessary including: 

  * To protect ourselves from liability, or
  * To respond to legal process or comply with law.

CDCK currently has no plans to engage in any form of advertising or targeting of users, however, our hosted forums may. Please refer to the privacy policy of the hosted forum. 

### 4\. CHANGES TO THIS STATEMENT

CDCK has the discretion to update this privacy statement at any time. We will make a good faith effort to notify the public of any changes. We encourage you to periodically review this privacy statement to stay informed about how we are helping to protect the personal information we collect. Your continued use of the service constitutes your agreement to this privacy statement and any updates. 

This document was last updated June 26, 2013. 

### 5\. CONTACTING US

If you have questions regarding our Privacy Statement, its implementation, failure to adhere to this Privacy Statement and/or our general practices, please contact us at team@discourse.org
